Commanders family, welcome in to free
agency Fridays. We are here in the Big
Bear AI Command Center studio with
possibly the biggest free agent in AP's
GM history, man. Odafe Oway in the
building, brother. First things first,
congratulations, man. How you feeling?
>> Feeling good. You know, it's an out of
body feeling, but I feel good. I'm
blessed, man. Thanking God.
>> When you say out of body, what do you
mean by that? Because this is your first
time going through a free agency process
for real, right?
>> Yeah. And that's more so because the
reason, you know, it's my first time
doing it. Um, growing up, you always see
free agency and it's like, damn, what if
I was in that position and I was finally
got that opportunity this this offseason
and it was crazy, you know, just having
someone want to, you know, wanting your
expertise, wanting to, you know, have
you part of their organ or organization,
everything. It's it's it's good to feel
wanted. So,
>> what were those things that they said
here that sounded right to you that made
you say, you know what, I want to
continue my career here in Washington?
um just just the you know the dedication
to you know my plan and what I want to
bring to the you know the team you know
I want to I want to bring sacks I want
to bring you know gamechangasing plays
and you know they're they were adamant
and telling me that you know they want
to help me do that. Um coach coach Dan
Quinn you know he's he's a he's a um a
family guy you know he wants to get to
know you he wants to relate with you and
I that really connected to me. So cuz I
feel like if you want to be dominant on
the field you got to everyone has to be
you know connected has to have a
camaraderie and you know like each other
for it to be dominant on the field. So,
I got that connection
>> and I got to imagine it helps too having
a guy like Dan Quinn who's defense
first, right? Who is a defensive guy
when you guys do have those
conversations? How has he been talking
to you about how he is going to get the
most out of you and get the best out of
you?
>> Yeah, just attack mentality.
>> Um, keep on going, going, going, playing
forward, not trying to think too much.
>> Um, just play physical fast and that's
type of that's type of defense I love.
We thrive in cuz, you know, I love I
love getting off the ball. I love just,
you know, attacking, trying to be
disruptive. So that's what he's, you
know, told me about and and I'm excited
about it.
>> And let's go to last year because I
think around week six, you end up
getting traded from the Baltimore Ravens
to the LA Chargers. Now in Baltimore at
this point, you have zero sacks, but
then you go to the Chargers, get seven
and a half sacks, I think three sacks,
two force fumbles in the playoffs, which
is a Chargers record. You know what I'm
saying? We do our research here, man.
When you're able to do that, get traded,
right? Because that's not always easy.
That's it's a little tough when you
don't expect to go somewhere else. But
what went right last year when you did
get traded? Um, I mean it's all about
just how you adjust and how you take
adversity. Obviously, um, you know, it
was a tough look and everything. Um,
obviously it was not what I wanted at
the beginning of the season, but um, I
had a decision go left to go right and
um, I decided to go right and um,
>> believe in God that, you know, if I if I
continue believing who I am and continue
to not cheat the cheat the game, put the
work in, that the results are going to
show. And you know they they did and I
thank God for that.
>> It's crazy sometimes God's plan so much
bigger than our plan and thank goodness
he has a plan because it ended up
working out right like again you go the
last time we see you on the field you
broke a record right you're out there
balling out. What about those big time
moments brings the best out of Odaf?
>> Um just like you know that's just my
like I've always just been doubted
always just been trying to like prove
that you know that um you know I'm the
guy that can make that play. So whenever
those moments come, I've been trying to
study them and just understand like when
could be the moment that if you make the
play, yo, it's going to it's going to be
crazy. Everyone's going to like go
crazy. So, and I like I really like like
I really want those moments. So, um
whenever I I can see them coming, I get
I get like goosebumps. So, you know,
when the crowd goes crazy, I know it's
turning down, you know, the the the
microphone going crazy, I just lock in
and go in a different mode. Yeah. And
you said you've always had this prove it
mentality.
>> Now that you're at this point, right,
where you've gotten that bag, a
four-year deal, which is AP's longest
contract he has given a free agent as a
GM, do you still feel like you have to
prove it?
>> Oh, yeah. Cuz now everyone's like, "What
you going to do with it, bro?" You know,
it's like everyone's going to know what
you going to do with it. And I and I got
something to myself that I always want
more. So I feel like I left some on the
table. So, um, I just feel like I could
have had way more sacks up until this
point. I could have had way more than
game changer plays up until this point.
So, now it's time to to show that, you
know, you've learned from the mistakes
and let's see what you're going to do
with that. So, yeah.
>> It's crazy to think that you have more
to do when you hear seven and a half
sacks, right? Like, it's crazy to think
like, yo, I'm still hungry for more.
What work have you put in to be able to
reach that plateau and be able to say,
you know what, I have done enough.
>> Yeah. Um,
I mean, it's I feel like it's never
really enough for real. It's but that's
subjective, you know, like I had seven
and a half, but that was half a season.
>> Imagine, you know, if I was locked in
the first five, so I think about stuff
like that. But at the same time, I'm
grateful that I was able to get that in
that time period and limited amount of
games, too, because that's that's a feat
as well. So, it's it's having a balance
and that's that's where I try to find my
balance because it can get crazy when
you always trying to like, oh no, you
should have done this, you should have
had 13, 14, 15. So, find that balance.
Yeah. And we have a new defensive
coordinator in Donte Jones who went out
and clearly got some of his guys on this
defense, you being the biggest one that
we got so far. How do you expect a guy
like Donte Jones to get the best out of
you?
>> Uh, you know, he told me he's just going
to not, you know, have me thinking too
much. Let me go go forward. Uh, be
aggressive. And, um, you know, he he
runs this type of defense that allows
the passers to be aggressive. So, you
know, the back end is doing their thing
and I I already believe that they're
going to be dominant, you know,
strapping up. So, um, you know, I'm
excited. You know, he just let me know
that we're ready. We're going all in and
we're trying to attack.
>> Yeah.
>> And you fit that mode of that versatile
defensive player that he wants because
as good as you are against the pass and
rushing the quarterback, you were just
as good stopping the run, if not even
better.
>> What makes you take pride in both sides
of those games? Because a lot of times
you see a guy, he's a onetrick pony, but
it seems like you do it all.
>> No, it's really um just coming in. I was
labeled as a run stopper um you know
type of end and that's what I was at
Penn State
>> and obviously the flag is oh but can he
rush the passer so then offseason that's
what I started training
>> I'm all that's all I'm doing just trying
to rush rush the passer it worked out
you know so once I took one offseason
just do pass rushing and I'd always been
a run stopper it just started you know a
meshing and I started being this
complete player and then I had to learn
how to drop too and you know I haven't
got a pick yet but
>> maybe this year
>> I'll learn all that yeah I'm I'm going
to work on my drops my hands to see
maybe this year will happen.
>> And you're joining in the defensive line
room with so many dogs, man. You got
Javon Kinlaws, Don Payne, Doris
Armstrong. There's so many people that
they just added in from outside the
building to come up in here. But what
makes Odaf Ooway different? What makes
you one of one?
>> Um, I mean, there's a whole bunch of
dogs there. Um, like, so I know they're
all different and there are different
rights, but for me, you know, I'm just
um like I started late. I started
football, you know, when I was a junior.
So, I got a different drive in terms of
trying to like make up space for guys
that, you know, have played their whole
lives. And then, you know, um I'm just
I'm fast, you know, I'm twitchy. Um you
know, I just feel like I have a I have
just a different swag to my game. I do
in an unorthodox way. I play I pass rush
in an unorthodox way. So, um I feel like
that's what makes me different. You
know, I don't pass rush as as the same
way as everyone else. So, and then that
right that makes me a little bit
different.
And then when you do come in here and
you get paid and you are that premier
free agent, there's an expectation put
on you. Right or wrong, there's an
expectation put on you by media, by the
fan base. But I got a feeling the
expectation you put on yourself is much
greater than that. Is that true?
>> Yeah, it has to be cuz at the end I'm
the one going out there to do that, man.
Like and you know, I've been I've been
through seasons where like I've had a
lot of expectations and I've had um
seasons where I've fall fallen short and
you know, seasons where I've superseded
expectations. So, you know, it's all
about being balanced and understanding
that whatever the outcome is, you can
always get better. And, you know, you
can't prepare yourself for what the next
season's going to show. So, like, as
long as you know you you came out the
the last adversity strong and, you know,
head high, chest up, the next one, you
know, you going to be good. You going to
be straight.
>> And even talking to you now, I can see
why they wanted to bring you in because
as great as you are on that field, I
think you're going to be just as good of
a leader and a mentor to a lot of the
young guys we have on that defensive
line. and we have a few in closing.
Are you ready for that part of this as
well? Being that mentor, being that
leader, because it seems like you're
ready to rise to occasion in that regard
as well.
>> Yeah, I just feel like I've been through
a lot in terms of just, you know, just
just understanding how how how to be
like a a rookie, a second year, third
year, fourth year in the league. It's
just different levels of understanding
how to play it. So, um I can I can give
that to give some game to the younger
guys. Um but, you know, I'm more so like
a lead by example type guy. So, cuz I
know these are these are all alpha
males. These are all guys that they got
here for a reason. A lot of guys don't
like being told what to do. But at the
same time, if you continue to show them
like what you're doing is the right way
and you're having, you know, success
with that, you know, people going,
people going to follow.
>> Man, we are so excited to see you a part
of this defense, man. I'm telling you,
Commander fans, can't wait to hear from
you and just we appreciate you taking
the time to jump up on here, man, and
talk to you.
>> Yes, sir. Congratulations, man, on the
big deal, man. That is major. You earned
that. My brother Commander family, our
next man up, part of free agency
Fridays, Odaf Ooway in the building,
ready to disrupt some offenses in the
NFL, man. We appreciate you, dog. Yes,
sir. Is it?